[Music]
Welcome to this busy central launch
event 20125 release day one. In this
session, we will introduce
uh you to one small but very nice
feature in
sustainability using default values on
different master data. When I say
different values, different
sustainability values. Okay, to start
with that first what do you need to do?
You need to move to sustainability setup
to enable these default values and why
you need to do that because just imagine
you do not want to use sustainability or
you do not want to use maybe these
default values. So in this case for you
it will be business as usual because by
default it will be disabled only if you
want to use you will system will
automatically change us your experience
and you will see some new fields. So
what you need to do in sustainability
setup you will find procurement fast tab
and there you will find four different
uh fields for general ledger uh
enablement item resource and working
machine center enablement. You will find
fifth one for item charge but currently
this is disabled by default. You cannot
enable in this moment. I will explain
why. So what do you need to do? You just
need to enable these fields and all
these default values will be visible on
these different master data. So what you
will get on GL account you will get only
sustainability account as default value.
So you can add only sustainability
account there because there is no reason
to add emission values in in general
edure account because all the time
probably you will have different uh
values when you want to post something.
But for all other uh cards on item card,
resource card, B and machine center
cards, you can set up uh either uh not
either both uh sustainability account
and three the different gas emissions
default values. You can change them
later when you're working, but you will
have default values there all the time.
And as I promise uh to explain for item
charge in this moment, you can see this
is uh gray uh on the screen. Item charge
is not enabled yet in this moment. It
will be part of next wave because
completely uh functionality about value
chain is currently public preview. So we
didn't want to enable uh before we
completely uh finish this uh
functionality. So this is just for you
to know what you can expect. So in next
way we will enable item charge. So now I
will move to my colleague Melissa so she
can show you how it works in the
practice. Thank you Alexander. Now let's
show you the demo. Let's start from the
item setup. I will go to item list and
take one item. We'll take the first one.
And now we need to move to
sustainability group
part and add default sustainability
account. These default emission fields
are related to replenishment system
field. So if our replenishment system is
set to production order or assembly,
these fields are non-editable and system
will calculate them. But if we change it
to the purchase, these fields are now
editable and we can update them
manually. I will add some
values for carbon equivalent per unit
field. Uh as our item is the new one, we
haven't used it yet. Uh we need to
update this field using action calculate
carbon
equivalent. I will run the action. And
once it is done, we can see that the
field is updated. Now let's move to
resources and do the same setup.
There I will take one
resource. In sustainability group we add
default sustainability account and also
we update default gas emissions
fields. Here we also need to run action
calculate carbon equivalent in order to
update our field. Once it is
done, we can move to charts of account.
The same action calculate carbon
equivalent exist also on the list. But
running it on the list, it will update
all
resources. I will move to charts of
accounts and do the setup for one jail
account. I will take
my GL
account. And here you can see that I
already added a default sustainability
account. Now once we finish the settings
we can go to purchase
invoice. I have already created the
one. Now I can update it and add some
lines. I will add our
item. And here you can see that the
default sustainability account has been
transferred from the item
card. I will add
quantity and unit
cost. And when we move to emissions
fields, we can see that default emission
fields are transfer also from the item
card. These fields are only default
values, but we can modify them. So we
can change sustainability account to
different one and also emissions can be
changed. Now let's add one
resource. I will choose the resource
that we already
set. Here you can see the sustainability
account number is transfer from the
resource card. And when we add
quantity and unit
cost other default values are also
updated. I will add one more line. It is
GL
account. I will choose my GL
account. And here we can also see that
sustainability account number has been
updated based on GL account setup.
But we don't have for GL accounts we
don't have default values for total
emissions. So we need to add them
manually
here. Uh this feature now we presented
on purchase invoice but it is also
available on other uh documents such as
purchase order, purchase return order or
purchase credit me. Uh that concludes my
part. Now I will hand it back to
Alexander to continue. Thank you Melissa
for showing this demo and uh we are on
the end of this session. Before I close
this session, I would like to invite you
to watch another uh sustainability and
other sessions as well. But we have this
year eight different sustainability
recordings. So please watch all of them
if you're interesting in sustainability
topic. So thank you for watching this
video.